No toy gets left behind.
Toy Story 3 is a animation, family, comedy film directed by Lee Unkrich.
Woody, Buzz, and the rest of Andy's toys haven't been played with in years.
With Andy about to go to college, the gang find themselves
accidentally left at a nefarious day care center.
The toys must band together to escape and return home to Andy.
Woody (voice), played by Tom Hanks.
Buzz Lightyear (voice), played by Tim Allen.
Jessie (voice), played by Joan Cusack.
Mr. Potato Head (voice), played by Don Rickles.
Rex (voice), played by Wallace Shawn.
Hamm (voice), played by John Ratzenberger.
Toy Story 3 is a 2010 American animated adventure comedy-drama film
produced by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures.
Directed by Lee Unkrich and written by Michael Arndt, it is the third installment
in the Toy Story film series and the sequel to Toy Story 2 (1999).
The film features the voices of Tom Hanks, Tim Allen, Joan Cusack, Don Rickles, Wallace
Shawn, John Ratzenberger, Estelle Harris, Jodi Benson, and John Morris.
In the film, Andy Davis, now a teenager, is going to college.
Woody, Buzz Lightyear and the other toys are accidentally donated to the Sunnyside Daycare
center by Andy's mother, and the toys must decide where their loyalties lie.
In 2004, following disagreements between the Walt Disney Company's CEO Michael Eisner and Pixar CEO Steve Jobs, Disney planned to make
Toy Story 3 at the new Circle Seven Animation studio unit, with the tentative theatrical release date in early 2008.
The script was developed in multiple versions; however, after Disney bought Pixar in early 2006, the
Circle Seven version of the film was canceled as the result of Circle Seven's closure.
The production was then transferred to Pixar, where a new script was developed.
Randy Newman returned to compose the film's musical score.
With a budget of $200 million, Toy Story 3 is one of
the most expensive films ever made.
Toy Story 3 premiered at the Taormina Film Fest in Italy on June 12,
2010, and was released in the United States on June 18.
It was the first film to be released theatrically with Dolby Surround 7.1 sound.
Like its predecessors, the film received acclaim from critics, with praise for the vocal
performances, screenplay, emotional depth, animation, and Newman's musical score.
It grossed $1.067 billion worldwide, finishing its theatrical run as the highest-grossing film of
2010 and the fourth-highest grossing film of all time at the time of its release.
It was also the first animated film to reach $1 billion at the box office, and was the highest-grossing animated film until
the release of Frozen in 2013, and Pixar's highest-grossing film until the release of Incredibles 2 in 2018.
The National Board of Review, the American Film Institute and Cahiers du
Cinéma named Toy Story 3 one of their top ten films of 2010.
Amongst its numerous accolades, Toy Story 3 was nominated for five awards at the 83rd
Academy Awards, winning Best Animated Feature and Best Original Song.
One of those nominations was for Best Picture, thus making it the third and currently most recent
animated film to be nominated for this award, after Beauty and the Beast (1991) and Up (2009).
A sequel, Toy Story 4, was released in 2019.
The film explores themes of escape, hostage, college, villain, sequel.
The tone is lighthearted.